# **Troy Simon**

### Objective

Technical visionary with over 30 years experience developing IT strategy, architecture, R&D and the software development of mission-critical computing solutions is seeking to utilize award winning development and executive management experience in an environment that fosters innovation and encourages out-of-the-box thinking.

#### **Professional Skills**

**Technical:** Flutter, Swift, Objective-C, Java, JSON, XML, Web technologies, relational databases, distributed computing, workflow, desktop & enterprise integration and UI design, graphics programming, animation, real-time data, neural networks, genetic algorithms, compiler design, desktop architecture, data access abstractions, middleware, fault tolerant architectures, enterprise application integration.

**Business:** Exemplary business/technology leadership, technology strategy, relationship management and negotiation skills.

## **Functional Summary**

- · Manage software engineering departments
- Worked in large-scale application implementation projects
- · Develop enterprise solutions for complex systems
- Data mapping and synchronization techniques
- Complete project life-cycle including business needs analysis, design of architecture, development of data models, software development, data recovery plans, testing and implementation.
- Hands-on design and development of leading-edge software solutions for Internet,
   Startup, Chemical, Financial, Telecommunications, Airline and Pharmaceutical industries.

#### **Management Summary**

Manage software engineering departments. Worked in large-scale application implementation projects. Develop enterprise solutions for complex systems. Data mapping and synchronization techniques. Complete project life-cycle including business needs analysis, design of architecture, development of data models, software development, data recovery plans, testing and implementation. Hands-on design and development of leading-edge software solutions for Internet, Chemical, Financial, Telecommunications, Airline and Pharmaceutical industries.

## **Experience**

#### Founder/CTO Concierge Health

September 2019 - Dec 2022

- Developed a reimbursement platform that processed over \$3M per month in location and member Medicare/Medicaid reimbursements.
- Designed and developed a flutter based wellness social network, reimagining the timeline suited for the member, insurance carrier and vendors.

- Work as part of a cross-functional team, which includes user experience researchers and designers, product managers, back-end engineers, and other functional specialists.
- Evaluated and streamlined core IT systems to support millions of data requests. Retired obsolete apps, established scalable platforms supporting business growth and strengthened information security.
- Selecting and implementing the right tools, frameworks, languages, and technologies for the job, with a focus on open-source solutions.
- Built and managed talented teams of developers and other specialists. Supervised up to 25
  personnel per engagement, coordinating between in-house and client teams and keeping
  stakeholders informed of progress and milestones.

### Founder/Architect of Gym Farm LLC

August 2014 - September 2019

- Developed mobile member flutter application that works with NFC chip to provide a simple checkin process at the facility. The app also serves as the admin app for the club owners to check their month insurance payouts, manage members and employees.
- Designed and developed our flagship node js platform Health Data Network that connects 9000+ gyms, 12 gym management systems to join 13 million gym members across the platform for insurance reimbursement, hardware authentications.
- Developed a scalable service model that runs on top of the HDN that process 5.3 million reimbursements for insurance companies (Tivity Health, Humana, Optum Health) per day across 9000 gyms in the united states.
- Developed authentications services for 18300 gym hardware devices.
- Developed a web platform that provides a white label configurable mobile app solution for gym owners to develop their own custom native mobile applications using web drag and drop UI.

## Lead IOS Developer - Omni I On-Demand Storage & Delivery

November 2016 - February 2017

- Worked with a small developer team to develop the next generation of an on-demand storage mobile application and platform.
- Developed new features based on spec provided by UX designer.
- Migrated objective-c code to newer frameworks to use storyboard.
- Developed web based service models to consulate all network calls, error messages and data storage.

#### **Mobile Architect - Business Voice at Comcast**

October 2015 - September 2016

- Designed existing application migration roadmap from Objective-C to Swift leveraging existing platform domain knowledge.
- Designed development patterns for communication layers in the mobile application while interfacing with the web service groups.
- Hired and manage local and remote development teams for the project across three continents.
- Mentored team on design and best implementation strategies. Provide an environment
  where the developers could learn from each other and learn a secondary mobile language
  to support the primary project leaders and reduce downtime due to experience gaps in the
  team.
- Worked closely with a remote design firm, business partners, supporting technology groups and content managers.
- Worked with internal departments to ensure communication layer designs aligned (protocols, structures, error message)

## Lead Mobile Architect at OneLogin, Inc.

January 2014 - January 2015

- Primary role was to hire, manage and mentor mobile members.
- Provide an environment where the developers could learn from each other and learn a secondary mobile language to support the primary project leaders and reduce downtime due to experience gaps in the team.
- Programmed with the team to rewrite mobile applications and expanded the companies mobile footprint across all mobile device platforms (IOS/Android/Windows).
- Worked with other senior architects to develop a Native Application Platform that allowed native applications to have a single sign-on protocol for IOS, Android, Windows, Xamarin and HTML based mobile applications.

#### Senior Mobile Developer at Zillow.com

June 2012 - August 2014

- Worked with a team of developers on the newly release Zillow Rental application for iPhone and iPad.
- Developed using Objective-C and custom frameworks.
- Self managed as the majority of the team was in Seattle Washington.

#### Sr. Mobile Developer at RentJuice (Acquired)

#### **Consultant for Readevou Software**

March 2008 - January 2012

#### **Senior Architect - Lightning Gaming**

February 2006 - March 2008

## **Senior Architect/Developer at SBC Communications**

June 2004 - February 2005

## **Director of Engineering at Entigen**

January 2002 - December 2003

## Senior Architect/Developer at Vitria Technology

December 1999 - January 2002

## **Technology Senior Manager at Merrill Lynch**

1996 - 1999

## Education

Manhattan College

BA, Computer Science, September 1984 - May 1988 Activities and Societies: Track Team